

PROFILF

With over five years of work experience, I'm a passionate developer that learned life is much more than coding. Working with international teams since 2016, I really believe in the diversity and talent that a remote first

From low-level backend optimization to the UI & UX, I enjoy navigating the end to end spectrum of skills that a real-world solution requires so the well stablished silos of knowledge can be minimized.

environment brings to the table.

HARD SKILLS

C++
SQL
Linux
C
Javascript
Bash

SOFT SKILLS

Leadership

Communication

Troubleshooting

Problem Solving

TOOLS & SERVICES

Gitlab

Docker

Vim

CI/CD

GDB

Lucas Lemos

System Development Engineer @ Siemens | Software Developer C/C++, JS, SQL, Bash, Linux

me@lemosl.com.br

+55 41 99618-8104

https://lemosl.com.br

EXPERIENCES

System Development Engineer
Siemens / Curitiba-BR / 2021 - Present (3 years)

Data Modeling of CIM-based application in a framework built on top of Oracle, C++, Perl and Bash scripts. I'm involved in bug fixing, new features design and tightening the gap with other teams (SysAdmins, UI and System Architects)

SIEMENS

Junior System Development Engineer

Siemens / Curitiba-BR / 2018-2020 (2 years)

Joined a team that developed from the ground up a Self-Healing solution for the Distribution grid. Using internal technologies for the back and frontend, I became the "one-man band" that implemented features and talked to customers

SIEMENS

O Intern – R&D

TDK InvenSense / Grenoble-FR / 2018 (6 months) Developed a project to use an array of microphones to detect a sound source in 3D space. Started from researching academic papers in the literature to building a prototype of an MVP solution.



GIPSA Lab / Grenoble-FR/ 2017 (3 months)

I worked on a visual perception bio-inspired model to categorize natural vs. artificial images. An image was classified with a set of filter to mimic how human brain works. We experimented with classic image classification algorithms to understand how far it could go.



EDUCATION

Masters in Embedded System

Polytech Grenoble / 2016-2018



© Embedded System Engineer UFPR Curitiba ■ / 2012-2018



LANGUAGES

English
French
Portuguese